[indistinct conversations]
WHERE THE HELL IS HE,
STACE?
DON'T WORRY, MR. LYNCH.
I'M SURE HE'LL BE HERE SOON.
YEAH, WELL,
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I MEAN, HE GOES ON
IN LESS THAN FIVE MINUTES.MM.
[indistinct conversations
continue]
IT'S ALL RIGHT, MR. LYNCH.
HE'S HERE.
ALL RIGHT,
GET HIM UP ON STAGE
AND I'LL TELL EVERYBODY
HE'S ON HIS WAY.OKAY.
MR. BRAVA, I'M AFRAID
WE NEED TO HURRY.
MR. BRAVA, NO ADVANCE COPY
OF YOUR SPEECH
HAS BEEN RELEASED.
WHY THE SECRECY?WELL, COME HEAR IT,
AND YOU'LL KNOW.
CAN YOU TELL US ANYTHING
ABOUT WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO SAY?
YOU WANT A SOUND BITE?
FINE.
PEOPLE WHO TRAFFIC IN HUMANS
ARE LIKE COCKROACHES
HIDING IN THE DARK.[cell phone rings]
YOU HAVE TO EXPOSE 'EM
TO THE LIGHT.WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "EXPOSE"?
WILL YOU BE NAMING SOMEBODY?
MR. BRAVA.[camera shutters clicking]
WAIT HERE.UH, MR. BRAVA.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.[Stacey] MR. BRAVA!
[sighs]THAT WAS HECTOR BRAVA,
THE KEYNOTE SPEAKER
FOR THE HUMAN GLOBAL CONFERENCE.
[indistinct conversations
continue]
MR. BRAVA?
[sighs] WE REALLY HAVE TO...
HELP ME! SOMEBODY, PLEASE!
ANDY BURNSIDE--
KANE COUNTY SHERIFF.
AGENT TERESA LISBON. THIS IS
PATRICK JANE, OUR CONSULTANT.
HI.HI.
SO THE VICTIM'S NAME
WAS HECTOR BRAVA.
HE WAS A DO-GOODER.
RAN AN ORGANIZATION CALLED
THE SHELTERING LIGHT FOUNDATION.
THEY FIGHT HUMAN TRAFFICKING.
THERE'S A CONFERENCE
GOING ON.
HE WAS SUPPOSED TO GIVE
SOME KIND OF A SPEECH.
SO YOU'RE THE PSYCHIC, HUH?
NO.
NO SUCH THING AS PSYCHICS.
[camera shutter clicks]
[Cho] ALL RIGHT. THANKS.
[sighs]
LOOKS LIKE CAUSE OF DEATH
IS BLUNT FORCE TRAUMA
TO THE BACK OF THE HEAD.
YEAH, SOME OF MY MEN
FOUND A FIRE EXTINGUISHER
WITH BLOOD ON IT OVER THERE. NO,
UH, USABLE PRINTS ON IT, THOUGH.
IF HE WAS HERE TO MAKE A SPEECH,
WHAT WAS HE DOING BACK HERE?
THIS.
IT'S A TEXT MESSAGE.
"MEET ME THROUGH
THE STAFF DOOR. CARMEN."
TRACKING THE SENDER NOW.
HOW MANY CARMENS
HAVE YOU I.D.'d AT THE HOTEL?TWO EMPLOYEES AT THE HOTEL,
ANOTHER TWO WERE ATTENDING
THE CONFERENCE.
THEY ALL HAVE ALIBIS, THOUGH.
WE'RE GONNA KEEP LOOKING.
HE HAD HIS WALLET ON HIM,
ALL HIS CREDIT CARDS,
A LOT OF MONEY,
SO YOU CAN RULE ROBBERY OUT.MAYBE. WHERE'S HIS SPEECH?
HMM?
WELL, YOU JUST SAID BRAVA WAS ON
THE WAY TO DELIVER A SPEECH.
WOULDN'T HE HAVE THAT SPEECH ON
HIS PERSON, OR NOTES AT LEAST?
DID YOU FIND ANYTHING?NO.
FIND OUT EVERYTHING YOU CAN
ABOUT THE SPEECH.YOU GOT IT.
[moans]
WHAT?
UH,
THERE'S A CONTRADICTION HERE.
THE MURDER ITSELF
FEELS IMPROVISED--
THE FIRE EXTINGUISHER,
THE SEMIPUBLIC LOCATION.
BUT THE SETUP...
THE TEXT MESSAGE WAS PLANNED.
NO ROBBERY TO SPEAK OF.
NO ASSAULT OTHER THAN
THE BLOW TO THE HEAD.
IT DOESN'T FEEL LIKE
AN ANGER KILLING.
IT FEELS MORE LIKE
AN ACT OF DESPERATION.
THE MURDERER WANTED TO KEEP
BRAVA FROM DOING SOMETHING
OR SAYING SOMETHING.
THAT'S JUST
WHAT OUR PSYCHIC SAID.
YOUR PSYCHIC?KRISTINA FRYE.
YOU'RE KIDDING.
WHAT, YOU'VE HEARD OF HER?
[chuckles]
RELAX.
DON'T FORCE THE MEMORY.
IT'LL COME,
AND THE DETAILS WILL EMERGE.
HOW MUCH YOU PAYING HER,
SHERIFF?
THAT'S NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
OH, THAT MUCH? I'M WORKING
FOR THE WRONG PEOPLE.
MS. FRYE, HI.
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
YOU, TOO.
THANK YOU. WE'LL TALK LATER.
SO YOU GOT THE SHERIFF
WRAPPED AROUND YOUR FINGER.SHERIFF BURNSIDE IS A MAN
WITH AN ADMIRABLY OPEN MIND.
MM, YES. HE'S ALSO A MAN
THAT LIKES TO WATCH TELEVISION
WITH A CAT
CURLED UP ASLEEP ON HIS LAP
WHILE HIS MOTHER
SITS NEXT TO HIM AND KNITS.
BUT I'M SURE HE'D PREFER
THAT TO REMAIN A SECRET.
WELL, I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU WEREN'T PSYCHIC.[mouths words]
OH, HE IS. HE'S JUST
NOT READY TO ACCEPT IT.
ACTUALLY, IT WAS THE CAT HAIR
ON YOUR PANTS,
LACK OF WEDDING RING AND YOUR
GENERAL LIVE-WITH-MOM VIBE.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO BELIEVE
THAT HIS DEAD UNCLE HARRY
CAME DOWN AND WHISPERED IT
IN MY EAR, THEN BE MY GUEST.DON'T YOU EVER GET TIRED
OF YOUR OWN CYNICISM?OH, WEARY AS HELL.
WHAT'S THE ALTERNATIVE?
WHY DON'T WE GIVE THEM A LITTLE
BIT OF TIME TO CATCH UP?
SORRY ABOUT THE MOM THING.
♪♪
[Patrick] I HAVE A QUESTION.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WORKING WITH THE COPS?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
A SPIRITUAL PSYCHOANALYST.
DID YOUR PATIENTS
CATCH ON TO YOU?[chuckles]
I STILL HAVE MY PRACTICE.
WHY, YOU LOOKING
FOR A THERAPIST?UH,
LET ME THINK ABOUT THAT.
NO. I HEARD THAT
PSYCHOANALYSTS ARE A DISEASE
THAT PRESENT THEMSELVES
AS A CURE.
AND ON TOP OF THAT,
YOU ADD IN GHOSTS.
REFLEXIVE MOCKERY--A SIGN
OF A TROUBLED SOUL, PATRICK.
YOU GOT BORED, DIDN'T YOU?
GOT TOO EASY
TAKING THEIR MONEY.
NO. I THINK OUR GIFT
OBLIGES US TO HELP OTHER PEOPLE.
OH, IS THAT WHAT YOU THINK?
MM-HMM.OUR GIFT GIVES US
AN OBLIGATION TO HELP.
I LIKE THAT LINE.
I'M GONNA USE IT.VAN PELT SAYS
THERE'S A PROBLEM
TRACING THE TEXT MESSAGE
THAT BRAVA GOT.WHAT?
WELL, THE TRAIL LEADS
TO AN ELECTRONIC DEAD DROP.
NO WAY TO TRACE IT BACK.
BUT SHE'S GONNA LOOK
AT HIS OTHER PHONES,
RUN DOWN THOSE CALLS.AND WHAT ABOUT THE SPEECH?
THERE'S NO WORD YET ON WHETHER
HE HAD IT ON HIM OR NOT.
BUT WE HAVEN'T TALKED
TO THE WIFE YET. SHE'S INSIDE.[British accent]
HECTOR AND I KNEW
SOMETHING LIKE THIS
MIGHT HAPPEN. HE ALWAYS SAID
THERE WAS TOO MUCH AT STAKE
TO WASTE TIME WORRYING.WHAT WERE YOU AND YOUR HUSBAND
WORRIED ABOUT?
THE TRAFFICKERS--
PEOPLE WHO PROFIT
FROM THE ENSLAVEMENT OF OTHERS.
HECTOR WAS TIRELESS
IN HIS PURSUIT OF THEM.
IS THERE ANYONE YOU CAN THINK OF
WHO MAY HAVE WANTED TO KILL HIM?
AGENT, MY HUSBAND'S RECEIVED
HALF A DOZEN DEATH THREATS
SINCE CHRISTMAS.
IF YOU'RE ASKING FOR NAMES,
WELL, WE DIDN'T MAKE A HABIT
OF FILING THE NOTES.
HE WAS GONNA GIVE A SPEECH
TODAY. DID HE HAVE IT ON HIM?
YES. WHY?
[Lisbon] WELL, THERE WAS
SOME SECRECY SURROUNDING IT.
UH, DO--DO YOU KNOW
WHAT HE WAS GONNA TALK ABOUT?
NO, I DIDN'T.
THAT WASN'T UNUSUAL.
HECTOR RARELY SHARED THE DETAILS
OF HIS WORK WITH ME.
IT WAS HIS WAY
OF PROTECTING ME.
THE PERSON YOU NEED
TO TALK TO IS RUSSELL BIGELOW.
HE DID RESEARCH FOR HECTOR.
ILSA, UM...
[teacup clatters on table]
YOU'VE BEEN TOLD WHO I AM
AND WHAT I DO?
UH, YES.
MY COMMUNICATION
WITH THE OTHER SIDE IS LIKE
A LONG-DISTANCE PHONE CALL
WITH A BAD CONNECTION.
SO OFTEN THE MESSAGES I RECEIVE
ARE MEANINGLESS TO ME,
BUT NOT TO THOSE WITH ONES
WHO'VE PASSED OVER, OKAY?
I'M REALLY NOT BIG ON THIS, UM,
SUPERNATURAL STUFF.
YOU'RE NOT ALONE.
YOUR HUSBAND WANTS ME
TO REMIND YOU OF SOMETHING--
SOMETHING THAT WILL
MAKE YOU SMILE. IT'S, UH...
I'M GETTING AN IMAGE
OF, UM... CHERRY BLOSSOMS?
DOES THAT MEAN
ANYTHING TO YOU?
YES. UH...
WE WERE MARRIED
UNDER A CHERRY TREE.
HOW COULD YOU KNOW THAT?
HE CAN RECALL FOLIAGE
FROM HIS WEDDING DAY,
BUT HE CAN'T TELL YOU
WHO KILLED HIM?
CROSSING OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE
CAN BE CONFUSING.
IT'S A BIT LIKE WAKING UP
FROM ANESTHESIA.
SOMETIMES IT CAN TAKE A WHILE
TO GET REAL CLARITY.
HUH. OH, WELL, MAKES SENSE.
DOES THE NAME CARMEN
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU?
UH, THE OPERA. WHY?
[exhales deeply][wind chimes tinkle]
THAT'S PRETTY.
UH, MY TURN.
ILSA... DID YOUR HUSBAND
EVER CHEAT ON YOU?
DID YOU CHEAT ON HIM?
WHY WOULD YOU ASK THAT?
YOU--YOU'RE VERY NOBLE
AND--AND DIGNIFIED.
VERY STOIC.
A JACKIE O. THING
GOING ON THERE.
UH, MAYBE YOU DON'T
GIVE A CRAP.
MAYBE YOU'RE HAPPY
HE'S DEAD.
[glass shatters]
MAYBE NOT.
I'D LIKE YOU TO LEAVE NOW.
GOOD IDEA.
JANE, ENOUGH FUN. LET'S GO.
YEAH.
[slurps]
THANK YOU FOR THE TEA.
VERY TASTY.[teacup clatters]
[Lisbon] COME ON.
[Teresa] NICE WORK.
SHE WAS HIDING SOMETHING.
I WANTED TO SEE WHAT IT WAS.
AND WHAT'D YOU LEARN?WELL, IT'S EARLY DAYS.
SHE'S GOT A GOOD ARM.DID LEARN THAT.
I'M--I'M NOT SO SURE
THIS IS SUCH A GOOD IDEA
I TALK ABOUT THIS STUFF.
I-I-I'M JUST A RESEARCHER,
YOU KNOW? I...LISTEN, MR. BIGELOW,
WE UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU'RE FRIGHTENED,
BUT WE REALLY NEED TO KNOW
WHAT WAS IN THAT SPEECH.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND. LOOK,
TRAFFICKING GENERATES BILLIONS.
I MEAN, THERE ARE GOVERNMENTS
BEHIND THIS STUFF.
IT'S LIKE THESE PEOPLE
CAN GET TO ANYBODY.
I MEAN, HECTOR'S DEATH
ALREADY PROVES THAT.THEN WE CAN OFFER YOU
PROTECTION, RUSSELL.
BUT ONLY IF YOU TELL US
WHAT YOU KNOW.
IF YOU DON'T HELP US,
THEN ALL THE WORK
THAT YOU'VE DONE TO STOP
THESE GUYS WILL BE FOR NOTHING.
TRAFFICKERS USE
QUASI-LEGIT BUSINESSES
TO LAUNDER THEIR MONEY
AROUND THE WORLD.
I WATCH AUDIT TRAILS.
WE MADE A CONNECTION.
THAT'S WHAT'S
IN HECTOR'S SPEECH.
WHAT CONNECTION?
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD
OF THE WORLD
ANTI-TRAFFICKING COALITION?
ONE OF THE BACKERS
OF THE CONFERENCE, RIGHT?
YEAH. A MAJORCHARITY.
IT'S RUN BY A GUY NAMED
CHRISTOPHER LYNCH.
THEY ASSISTED US IN SHUTTING
DOWN A BUNCH OF NETWORKS,
BUT THE TRAFFICKING CONTINUED.
THE MONEY JUST WENT
SOMEPLACE ELSE.
SO IT TOOK A WHILE TO TRACE IT,
BUT WE FOUND OUT
THE COALITION IS A FRONT
FOR A TRAFFICKING GROUP.
YOU KNOW, THEY USED US TO
SHUT DOWN THEIR OWN COMPETITION,
BUILDING THEMSELVES A MONOPOLY.
HERE.
THAT THE SPEECH?MY COPY.
AND WHY DIDN'T YOU
NOTIFY THE AUTHORITIES
ONCE YOU FIGURED OUT
WHAT WAS GOING ON?'CAUSE HECTOR SAID
THAT HE WANTED TO DENOUNCE LYNCH
HIMSELF, IN PUBLIC.
I SAID IT WAS TOO DANGEROUS,
BUT HE JUST WOULDN'T LISTEN.
DID BRAVA EVER MENTION
ANYBODY NAMED CARMEN TO YOU?
NO. NO, NOT TO ME.
WHY?
SO BIGELOW IS SAYING
THAT THE PEOPLE
FIGHTING HUMAN TRAFFICKING
WERE TRAFFICKERS.APPARENTLY.
ALL RIGHT. YOU AND CHO
GO TALK TO THIS LYNCH.
SEE WHAT HE HAS TO SAY
FOR HIMSELF.OKAY, YOU GOT IT.
[indistinct conversations]
[man] ARE YOU GUYS JOKING?
BECAUSE YOUR HUMOR'S
IN BAD TASTE.
HECTOR WAS A CLOSE COLLEAGUE
AND A GOOD FRIEND.
WHO WAS PLANNING TO GIVE
A SPEECH THAT WOULD IDENTIFY
YOUR COALITION AS A FRONT FOR
HUMAN TRAFFICKERS, MR. LYNCH.HE NAMED YOU SPECIFICALLY.
[laughs] LOOK,
SOMEONE IS LEADING YOU DOWN
THE GARDEN PATH, GENTLEMEN.
OKAY, THERE'S NO BASIS
OF TRUTH IN THIS.
SURELY YOU CAN SEE THAT IT'S
IN THE TRAFFICKERS' INTEREST
TO SPLIT US UP,
GET US SUSPECTING EACH OTHER.
LOOKS LIKE BRAVA
WENT PAST SUSPECTING YOU.OH, PLEASE. HECTOR SAW
CONSPIRACIES EVERYWHERE.
YOU KNOW, HE LIKED
BEING IN THE SPOTLIGHT.WE READ THE SPEECH.
IT MAKES
A PRETTY CONVINCING CASE.OKAY, LOOK. WE'RE GONNA
CLEAR THIS UP RIGHT NOW.
I WILL HAVE MY LAWYERS GIVE YOU
ACCESS TO ALL OUR RECORDS,
AND THEN YOU WILL SEE
THAT THE COALITION
HAS NOTHING TO HIDE.DOES THE NAME "CARMEN"
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU?
NO.CAN YOU THINK OF ANYBODY
WHO'D WANT TO KILL BRAVA?
OH, YEAH, MAYBE
ONLY A FEW HUNDRED PEOPLE.
I JU--UH, WAIT A SECOND.
ONE THING.
SECOND NIGHT
OF THE CONVENTION,
I SAW HECTOR HAVING AN ARGUMENT
WITH A MAN NAMED TARIQ SHARIF
OUTSIDE THE HOTEL BAR,
AND FOR MY MONEY,
THE ARGUMENT WAS ABOUT A WOMAN.
HOW COULD YOU TELL?BECAUSE I KNOW THESE GUYS,
AND THEY DEFINITELY WEREN'T
HAVING A DISCUSSION
ABOUT IMMIGRATION POLICY.
HOW'S IT COMING WITH LYNCH?SAYS A MAN CALLED TARIQ SHARIF
WAS FIGHTING WITH BRAVA.
I'M CHECKING FOR AN I.D.
ON SHARIF RIGHT NOW.I TOOK A LOOK AT THE RECORDS
THAT LYNCH'S LAWYER
E-MAILED OVER. FIRST GLANCE,
COULDN'T FIND ANYTHING THAT
SUPPORTS BRAVA'S ACCUSATIONS.I CHECKED
LYNCH'S PHONE RECORDS.
HE MADE A SINGLE CALL
RIGHT AFTER WE LEFT
THE INTERVIEW TO AN ANONYMOUS
DISPOSABLE CELL.DOES IT SAY
WHERE IT ORIGINATED?
HERE'S THE WEIRD THING...THE CALL ENDS AT A CELL TOWER
OUT IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
THAT IS WEIRD.RIGHT? SO WE FIGURED
MAYBE WE'D GO CHECK IT OUT.
ALL RIGHT.HERE WE GO. I GOT HIM.
HERE'S TARIQ SHARIF.
♪♪
I'LL SEE
IF ANYBODY'S SEEN SHARIF.
EXCUSE ME.
[Lisbon]
HAVE YOU SEEN HIM?
HE'S ABOUT 6'2",
GRAY HAIR, MUSTACHE?
HE'S BY THE POOL.OKAY.
♪♪
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?NOTHING.
MR. SHARIF?
YES?
WE'RE WITH THE CBI.
AGENT LISBON. MR. JANE.
WON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
WELL, DON'T MIND IF WE DO.
I WAS JUST TELLING MR. SHARIF
THAT HIS SPIRIT IS TROUBLED.
THERE'S A WRONG
THAT HE BURNS TO RECTIFY.
MM, INTERESTING.
HECTOR WAS AN OLD FRIEND.
I, UH, PUSHED HIM
TO TAKE UP
THE TRAFFICKING PROBLEM.
NATURALLY,
I FEEL RESPONSIBLE.THEY'RE GREAT GLASSES.
YEAH.COULD--COULD I TRY THOSE?
UH, NO.OKAY.
MR. SHARIF, WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE OFF THE SUNGLASSES?
[chuckles]
NOW.
[sighs]
[Patrick] OH![glasses clatter]
YOU GOT A... OWIE.
IT WAS A MISUNDERSTANDING.
HE WAS DRUNK.
IT DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH ILSA, BY ANY CHANCE?
[chuckles]
IT WAS NOTHING LIKE THAT.IT WAS EXACTLY LIKE THAT.
YOU HAVE A STRONG CONNECTION
WITH ILSA--A BOND.
SEE?
[sighs and clears throat]
ILSA AND I WERE VERY CLOSE.
UH... [exhales deeply]
BY CHANCE, WE FOUND OURSELVES
HERE ALONE ON THE FIRST NIGHT.
I EXPRESSED
MY DEEP ADMIRATION FOR HER.
SHE RETURNED MY FEELINGS
BUT WAS AFRAID TO ACT ON IT.
HECTOR FOUND OUT.
HYPOCRITE THAT HE IS,
HE ATTACKED ME.
HOW IS HE A HYPOCRITE?BECAUSE HE WAS UNFAITHFUL
TO HER.
MM. I DID SAY.
MR. SHARIF, YOU WERE SAYING
THAT MR. BRAVA WAS UNFAITHFUL?
I'M A PACIFIST, NOT A COWARD.
YOU DON'T STRIKE ME
WITHOUT REPERCUSSIONS.
I WENT TO HIS SUITE
THE NIGHT BEFORE HE DIED
TO CONFRONT HIM.
A WOMAN WAS LEAVING.
IT WASN'T ILSA.
WAS IT SOMEONE
FROM THE CONFERENCE?
[laughs] IT WASN'T THAT KIND
OF WOMAN.
SHE WAS YOUNG, PRETTY,
UH, CHEAP CLOTHES.
I ASSUME
SHE WAS A PROSTITUTE.CARMEN.
[Cho] FAR AS I CAN TELL,
THIS IS THE ONLY STRUCTURE
WITHIN A HALF MILE
OF THE CELL TOWER
LYNCH'S CALL STOPPED AT.
WELL, I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.NOPE. NOT A THING.
[sighs]
THINK THEY HAVE DOGS?
PROBABLY.
[sighs]
[grunts]
[muffled crying in distance]
HEY, LISTEN.
THERE.
[infant crying]
[grunts]
[thud, chains rattling]
[latch clicks]
[women scream]
[gasping and panting]
[crying]
[speaking indistinctly]
YOU HAVE MISREAD
THE SITUATION, AGENTS.
I AM ENTIRELY IGNORANT
OF WHATEVER IT IS
THAT YOU ARE ACCUSING ME OF. [Rigsby] YOU'RE LYING.
[papers rustle]
WE'VE GOT THE PHONE RECORDS.[file smacks]
YOU CALLED YOUR GOONS
AND TOLD 'EM
TO LOCK THOSE WOMEN UP
SO YOUR GUYS COULD ESCAPE.I'M SORRY. GOONS? WHAT GOONS?
AND RECORDS CAN BE FAKED.
NO, THOSE WOMEN
IN THE TRUCK--THAT WAS YOU.
HECTOR BRAVA--
THAT WAS YOU, TOO.[chuckles] YOU'RE WRONG.
I WEEP FOR
THOSE POOR SOULS YOU FOUND.
AND AS I SAID,
HECTOR WAS A DEAR FRIEND.WHAT ABOUT CARMEN?
WHO'S CARMEN?
AND WHERE'S MY LAWYER?
[clicks tongue] TOUGH.
SOCIOPATH.
WOLF AMONG THE SHEEP.
HE'S A CAUGHT WOLF NOW.
PHONE CALL'S ENOUGH
TO CONNECT HIM
TO ABOUT
20 DIFFERENT FELONY CHARGES,
NOT EVEN COUNTING
THE HOMICIDE.
HE'S GOING AWAY
FOR A LONG TIME.
SHE LIKES YOU, THAT ONE.
WHICH ONE?THE BLONDE ONE.
WHAT?AND YOU LIKE HER.
WHA--I'M NOT SO SURE I KNOW
WHERE THIS IS HEADED.[telephone ringing in distance]
YOU KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE THIS IS HEADED.
DO YOU EVER CONSIDER
DATING AGAIN? DO YOU?
HOW DID WE GET
TO THIS POINT SO QUICKLY?
I'M JUST SAYING, I THINK
IT WOULD BE A GOOD THING.
WHAT WOULD?
UH, CHARGING LYNCH WITH BRAVA'S
MURDER. HOW CLOSE ARE WE?
A CONFESSION WOULD HELP.WELL, WHY DON'T YOU ASK
ONE OF HER SPIRITS?
I'M SURE THEY'LL PROVIDE
THE EVIDENCE
THAT'S NEEDED. [chuckles]
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?THIS CASE IS SOLVING ITSELF
WITHOUT ME.
I HAVE ERRANDS TO RUN.
LISBON.
YEAH.
CHRISTOPHER LYNCH
DIDN'T KILL BRAVA.
NO. THE EMOTION HE WAS TRYING
TO CONCEAL WAS CONTEMPT.
LYNCH DIDN'T CONSIDER HIM
WORTH KILLING.
A DEEPLY EVIL MAN, BUT NOT ONE
WHO COMMITTED THIS CRIME.
MM.[elevator bell dings]
[elevator doors close]THANK YOU. [clears throat]
WHAT IF I DIDN'T SAY "SPIRITS"?
WHAT IF I SAID "INSTINCTS"?
WOULD THAT BE SOMETHING
YOU COULD ACCEPT?
OH, WELL, MAYBE.
'CAUSE THEY'RE TELLING ME
TO COME WITH YOU.
ARE THEY? WHY?'CAUSE THE LAST TIME
YOU SPOKE WITH ILSA ENGELS,
SHE THREW A TEACUP
AT YOUR HEAD.IT WAS A SAUCER.
IT WASN'T A TEACUP.
AND WHO SAID I'M GOING
TO SEE ILSA ENGELS?TELL ME THAT YOU'RE NOT.
SHE THINKS WELL OF ME.
I CAN COMMUNICATE
WITH HER HUSBAND.[chuckles]
AND SHE'LL ONLY TALK
TO YOU IF I'M THERE.
WELL, I GUESS I HAVE NO CHOICE
BUT TO BRING YOU ALONG WITH ME.
YOU THINK YOU MANIPULATED ME
INTO COMING WITH YOU, DON'T YOU?
[elevator bell dings]NO, I DON'T. I THINK YOU
MANIPULATED ME INTO THINKING
I MANIPULATED YOU
INTO COMING WITH ME.[elevator doors open]
OKAY, I'M JUST GONNA COME
STRAIGHT OUT, AND I'M GONNA SAY
I'M SORRY FOR THE, UH, OBNOXIOUS
INFIDELITY REMARKS EARLIER,
AND I HUMBLY BEG
YOUR FORGIVENESS.
MM.
SORRY.
WOULD YOU MIND TALKING TO US
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT TARIQ SHARIF?
HE WAS DRUNK. HE SAID THINGS
HE SHOULDN'T HAVE SAID,
AND I EXCUSED MYSELF
FROM HIS COMPANY.
AND THEN YOUR HUSBAND
PUNCHED HIM IN THE FACE.
I DIDN'T TELL HECTOR
TO HIT HIM,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE ASKING.
I WON'T PRETEND
I'M PARTICULARLY SAD
THAT HECTOR PUNCHED HIM.
HE SAID THINGS THAT HE--
HE ACTED LIKE A PIG
AND AN ASS.
A PIG AND AN ASS?
THAT CAN'T BE GOOD.
WE NEED TO ASK YOU AGAIN
ABOUT THE NIGHT
BEFORE HECTOR DIED.
[exhales deeply] I, UM...
I HAD A DEPARTMENT MEETING.
I STAYED UP IN BERKELEY.
AND, UM,
IS THERE ANY CHANCE
THAT A WOMAN COULD'VE BEEN
VISITING WITH HECTOR THAT NIGHT?
IF TARIQ SAID THAT,
HE'S LYING.
HE WOULDN'T DARE SAY THAT
IF HECTOR WAS STILL ALIVE.
IT'S DISGUSTING.
DISGUSTING.
UM, WELL,
I-I GUESS I SHOULD GO.
OKAY. WELL,
I STILL HAVE SOME BUSINESS
TO ATTEND TO HERE,
SO, UH...
YEAH, I'M GONNA CATCH
A CAB OUT FRONT.
OKAY.
OH, NICE CALL
ON THE CHERRY BLOSSOMS,
BY THE WAY.HOW SO?
THE WEDDING PHOTOGRAPH--
MARCH '97, D.C.
MARCH THROUGH TO APRIL
IS THE ANNUAL
CHERRY BLOSSOM FESTIVAL IN D.C.
PATRICK, YOU CREDIT ME
WITH FAR TOO MUCH CUNNING.
YOU'RE VERY GOOD.
VERY COMPELLING.
THANK YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
BYE.
LISBON.
MEET ME AT THE HOTEL BAR.
[snaps phone shut]
CHEERS. OH, SWEETHEART,
THERE YOU ARE. JOIN US.
UH, I'VE GOT US A ROOM,
AND OUR FRIEND HERE...
NOVELLA.
NOVELLA. SHE'S GONNA HELP US
EXPLORE SOME BOUNDARIES.
NO, SHE'S NOT.
WORK WITH ME, TERESA.
MM.
YOU'RE PRETTY, UH,
WELL, YOU'RE
PRETTY ADVENTUROUS, RIGHT?
BECAUSE MY--MY LADY,
SHE--SHE GETS
A LITTLE OUT THERE AT TIMES.GETTIN' THERE NOW.
LET'S GO UPSTAIRS AND SEE.
YOU JUST HAVE TO
WORK THINGS OUT WITH HOWIE.
OKAY. BARKEEP!
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
ANOTHER BOTTLE
OF THE GOOD STUFF?
UH, NO, THANKS. UH...
[whispers] YOU'RE THE PIMP?
HEY. NOT NICE.
WELL, BUSINESS MANAGER, THEN.
CONCERNED FRIEND.
WHATEVER. WE'D LIKE TO TAKE
OUR LITTLE SOIREE UPSTAIRS
TO A MORE PRIVATE LOCATION.
NOVELLA SAYS THAT
WE HAVE TO TALK TO YOU.
IF IT'S GONNA BE THE TWO OF YOU,
IT'S GONNA BE EXTRA.
[sighs]
SURE. SHE'S PAYING.
I SHOULD PROBABLY TELL YOU
THAT I AM AGENT
FOR THE CALIFORNIA
BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION.
OH, WOW.
SHE HAS A GUN, TOO.
AND HANDCUFFS.WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
THIS IS ENTRAPMENT.
I WANT A LAWYER.WHAT YOU WANT IS TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS PICTURE
AND TELL ME
IF YOU RECOGNIZE THIS MAN.
[sighs]
NOPE. NEVER SEEN HIM.
BUT THAT GUY--
HIM I RECOGNIZE.
HE WAS IN HERE GETTING A GIRL
JUST THE OTHER NIGHT.
NO. NO WAY.
LOOK, I MIGHT NOT BE DENZEL,
BUT I DO OKAY.
BESIDES, I COULDN'T AFFORD
A PROSTITUTE ON MY SALARY,
BELIEVE ME.NOT FOR YOU.
FOR YOUR BOSS, BRAVA.
IS THAT SOMETHING
YOU DID A LOT OF--
PROCURING WOMEN FOR HIM?
[scoffs]
WOW. THE MAN'S DEAD.
ARE YOU SERIOUSLY GONNA
DRAG HIS NAME THROUGH THE MUD
LIKE THIS?
I'M NOT LOOKING TO DESTROY
ANYBODY'S REPUTATION, RUSSELL.
I JUST NEED
TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
ILSA WAS BACK IN BERKELEY.
HE CALLED ME
AND SAID HE NEEDED ME
TO DO HIM A FAVOR.
HE COULDN'T GO DOWN
TO THE BAR HIMSELF,
BECAUSE SOMEBODY WOULD
RECOGNIZE HIM.
SOMEBODY COULD'VE
RECOGNIZED YOU.
NOBODY DID.
I WAS LUCKY.
IT WAS HARD FOR YOU.
SURE.
SURE, IT WOULD'VE BEEN EASIER
IF HE DIDN'T DO IT AT ALL,
BUT... [chuckles]
LOOK, A-ALL I COULD DO WAS JUST
KEEP HIM FROM GETTING CAUGHT.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU CAN TELL US ABOUT THE GIRL?
UH...
I THINK
HER NAME WAS... CLARET.
CLARET.IT'S FRENCH.
WHAT DID BRAVA MEAN
WHEN HE SAID
HE WANTED
TO MAKE IT REGULAR?
WELL, I MEAN, NOT,
LIKE, ACTUALLY REGULAR,
BECAUSE HE DIED AND ALL,
BUT EVERY THURSDAY AFTERNOON,
IT WAS GONNA BE.
HE HAD A PLACE UP
IN OAKLAND, HE TOLD ME.
DO YOU HAVE AN ADDRESS?
SURE. AND A KEY, TOO.
I THINK IT'S THIS ONE
ON THE LEFT.
YEAH.
[keys jangle]
[lock clicks]
SO WOULD YOU EVER,
UH... [sighs]
YOU KNOW...
PAY FOR SEX? NO.
YEAH. IT'S WEIRD, RIGHT?
WEIRD? NO. EXPENSIVE.
HEY.
CHECK THIS OUT.
"CARMEN."
BINGO.
[Lisbon] WHAT DO YOU GOT?
[Cho] WELL, WE TRACKED
CARMEN'S PHONE NUMBER.
IT'S AN APARTMENT RENTED
TO A SALLY ALVAREZ.SO "CARMEN" WAS JUST A NAME
SHE USED FOR WORK?
MM. ALVAREZ HAS BEEN PICKED UP
A COUPLE TIMES FOR SOLICITING,
ONCE FOR POSSESSION.
SHE SKIPPED ON THAT APARTMENT
ABOUT A MONTH AGO,
BUT HER P.O. GAVE US AN ADDRESS
THAT WAS GOOD AS OF LAST WEEK.CALL BURNSIDE. TELL HIM
WE'RE GONNA PICK HER UP.
HEY, BOSS. THERE WAS
A CARMEN REYES WHO CALLED BRAVA
ON HIS HOTEL PHONE TWICE
THE NIGHT BEFORE HE DIED.
LEFT HER NAME ON
THE HOTEL MESSAGING SYSTEM.THERE'S NO RECORD
OF SALLY ALVAREZ
CALLING THE HOTEL--
HOME OR CELL.WHERE DID THE CALL
ORIGINATE FROM?
SUNSET HORIZON MOTOR COURT
IN SAN DESIDERA.
A CARMEN REYES CHECKED IN
TWO DAYS AGO. SHE'S STILL THERE.ALL RIGHT.
THEN WE'VE GOT TWO LOCATIONS
TO LOOK FOR HER AT.OR WE HAVE TWO CARMENS.
TWO CARMENS?
TWO CARMENS.WHAT DOES THAT MEAN,
WELL, IT MEANS
THINGS ARE GETTING INTERESTING.
AH, WELL, AS LONG
AS IT'S INTERESTING FOR YOU.
I'LL GO WITH VAN PELT.
THERE'S JUST SOMETHING
ABOUT MOTELS--
OLD-FASHIONED AND ILLICIT,
BOTH AT THE SAME TIME.
IS THAT AN INVITATION?
WHOA. WELL, LOOK AT YOU, JUST
SHOWING UP LIKE A BAD PENNY.
I HAD A PREMONITION
YOU'D BE HERE.
REALLY?
NO. LISBON TOLD ME.
AH.
UPSTAIRS. 204.
GRACE, YOU KNOW KRISTINA?YEAH. HI.
[Kristina] HI.DID YOUR PSYCHIC POWERS
TELL YOU TO COME?
I DID HAVE AN INSTINCT
YOU WERE ABOUT TO GET
A BREAK IN THIS CASE.[Patrick] OH, I THINK
YOU MIGHT HAVE JUST
MADE AGENT VAN PELT'S DAY.[Van Pelt] WE'RE LOOKING
FOR CARMEN REYES.
ACTUALLY, WE HAVE
TWO ADDRESSES FOR HER.
THIS IS JUST ONE OF 'EM.
HER REAL NAME IS SALLY ALVAREZ.
WAIT A SECOND. SALLY ALVAREZ.
I KNOW THAT NAME.
SHE COMMUNICATED WITH ME
A SHORT TIME AGO.
SHE'S PASSED OVER.
I'M PRETTY SURE
SHE'S STILL IN THERE.
[knocks on door]
SALLY?
[knocks]SALLY?
OPEN IT UP.[lock clicks]
STEP BACK, SIR.[man] OH.
SHE'S DOWN.
HEY, CHO.[Cho]
We found Sally Alvarez.
SHE'S BEEN DEAD
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS.
Blunt force trauma
to the head.SHE'S DEAD? OH, MY GOD.
THAT'S AMAZING.
WHY?Kristina Frye said Sally
passed over. She predicted it.
SHE DID?YES.
CAN I HAVE THAT?
THANK YOU.
CHO, PLEASE DO NOT BELIEVE
THIS MYSTIC MUMBO JUMBO.
GULLIBLE GRACE BURIED THE LEAD.
[Patrick] I was right.
There were two Carmens.THERE WERE?
THAT'S RIGHT, AND WE HAVE
THE REAL ONE RIGHT HERE.
CARMEN REYES. SHE CLAIMS TO BE
HECTOR BRAVA'S DAUGHTER.
A YEAR AGO, MY MOTHER WAS
DIAGNOSED WITH CANCER.
UH, IT GOT BAD VERY FAST.
SHE WAS GONE
IN LESS THAN A MONTH.
BEFORE SHE DIED, SHE TOLD ME HECTOR BRAVA WAS MY FATHER.
AND AFTER THE FUNERAL, I WROTE TO HIM.
I NEVER HEARD BACK.
I THOUGHT
MAYBE HE'D FORGOTTEN HER.
I WROTE THERE WAS NOTHING
I WANTED FROM HIM,
ONLY TO MEET THE MAN
WHO WAS MY FATHER.
HE STILL DIDN'T ANSWER?
I SAW SOMEWHERE THAT HE WAS
DELIVERING A SPEECH HERE.
[chuckles] I THOUGHT
I'D GO CONFRONT HIM.
YOU WERE ANGRY.
I WANTED TO TALK TO HIM.
DID YOU?
WHEN?
THE MORNING HE DIED?
THE NIGHT BEFORE.
I WENT TO HIS SUITE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE LET ME IN.
HE WAS FRIENDLY,
UNTIL I TOLD HIM
I WAS HIS DAUGHTER.
HE GOT VERY UPSET
AND ANGRY.
[Carmen] HE SAID,
I COULD NOT BE HIS DAUGHTER.
HE SAID,
HE ALREADY MET HIS DAUGHTER,
AND WHAT KIND OF SCAM WAS I TRYING TO PLAY?
HE TURNED SO PALE
AND SHOOK ALL OVER.
HE THREW ME
OUT OF THE ROOM
AND LOCKED THE DOOR,
SO I LEFT.
AND THAT WAS LAST TIME
YOU SAW HIM?
ON THE NEWS,
IT SAID WHAT HAPPENED.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
AND WHAT ABOUT
THE TEXT MESSAGE?
DID YOU SEND THAT?
I DON'T HAVE A PHONE.
SO IS SHE TELLING
THE TRUTH?
I'M NOT SURE.
BRAVA'S SPIRIT IS
DEEPLY CONFLICTED.
I CAN'T GET A CLEAR READING.WHAT ARE YOU USING,
DIAL-UP?
[Lisbon] MY QUESTION IS,
IF SHE'S TELLING THE TRUTH,
WHY WAS SALLY ALVAREZ PRETENDING
TO BE CARMEN REYES?
I TALKED TO BIGELOW.
HE KEPT A RECORD
OF ALL WORK CORRESPONDENCES
BUT DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH BRAVA'S PERSONAL LETTERS.
THERE'S NO WAY TO KNOW
IF HER STORY CHECKS OUT OR NOT.IF BRAVA'S HER FATHER,
SHE'S GOT MOTIVE.
SHE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE.
[Ilsa]
I COULD NEVER HAVE CHILDREN.
IS IT TRUE?
IS SHE REALLY
HECTOR'S DAUGHTER?
WE DON'T KNOW, MA'AM.
SHE'S AGREED TO TAKE
A PATERNITY TEST.
I THINK SHE MIGHT BE
TELLING THE TRUTH.SO YOU THINK SHE MIGHT BE
THE ONE THAT KILLED HECTOR.
WELL, MAYBE...
AND THEN MAYBE IT WAS YOU.
I HAVE TO SAY, MA'AM,
I-IT'S PRETTY HARD TO BELIEVE
THAT YOU DIDN'T KNOW
ABOUT HIS BEHAVIOR.
YES, I KNEW. HECTOR WAS
A PASSIONATE AND HEROIC MAN
WHO DEVOTED HIMSELF
TO HELPING OTHERS.
HIS FLAWS WERE
CORRESPONDINGLY OVERSIZED.
AND HIS BEHAVIOR WAS OKAY
WITH YOU?
I ACCEPTED IT.
THE GOOD IN HIM OUTWEIGHED
THE BAD.
IF HE'D TOLD ME,
MAYBE I COULD'VE DONE
SOMETHING TO PREVENT IT.
MAYBE I COULD'VE SAVED HIM.WHAT FOR?
HOW COULD YOU NOT WANT
TO GET AWAY
FROM HIS SERIAL PHILANDERING,
FROM THE PRISON
OF YOUR LOVELESS MARRIAGE?THAT'S NOT TRUE!
I LOVED MY HUSBAND,
AND HE LOVED ME!
WELL, MAYBE WE CAN GET
IN CONTACT WITH HIM NOW.
YOU COULD DO THAT,
COULDN'T YOU?IT WOULD CERTAINLY CLEAR UP
A FEW THINGS.
WOULD YOU DO THAT?
WOULD YOU TALK TO MY HUSBAND?
YES, ILSA.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?WHAT DOES IT LOOK
LIKE I'M DOING?
OKAY, SO VAN PELT IS
BRINGING CARMEN.
RIGSBY'S GONNA BRING
RICHARD BIGELOW.
CHO IS GONNA PICK UP
TARIQ SHARIF AND STACEY.
SO WE'RE ALL SET.
WHAT'S ALL SET FOR WHAT?
WE'RE ALL SET
FOR, UH, KRISTINA FRYE
TO CONTACT
HECTOR BRAVA'S SPIRIT.I NEED EVERYBODY CONNECTED
WITH HIS PASSING.
OKAY. WELL, UH, I GUESS...
[clears throat][lowered voice]
NOW LISTEN, JUST MAKE SURE
BRAVA'S SPIRIT HAS A THIRST
FOR REVENGE.
HE WANTS TO PUT SOME KIND
OF A CURSE ON THE KILLER,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THAT KIND OF THING.
AND THEN I'LL TAKE IT
FROM THERE.I CAN'T DO THAT.
YES, YOU CAN.
IT IS A NECESSARY LIE.I CAN ONLY CONTACT
HECTOR BRAVA'S SPIRIT
AND SPEAK
AS HE WANTS ME TO.
TO DO OTHERWISE WOULD BE
TO ABUSE MY GIFT.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
YEP. EVERYTHING'S GOOD.
IT'S PERFECT.
[Ilsa] ARE WE STARTING NOW?
[Kristina] ALMOST.
I'LL JUST GET THE DOOR.
WELCOME.
[Patrick] COME ON IN.
THANKS FOR COMING.
IT WAS
YOUR HUSBAND'S REQUEST.
YOUR HUSBAND'S DAUGHTER.
[clears throat]
[sighs]
WELL, THANK YOU ALL FOR COMING.
PATRICK WILL BE
ASSISTING ME.
SO IN ORDER
FOR THIS TO WORK,
I NEED EVERYBODY
TO BE CALM AND FOCUSED.
I WANT YOU TO LOOK AT THE CANDLE
IN THE CENTER OF THE TABLE.
FOCUS ON THE FLAME
AND CONCENTRATE ON HECTOR.
[inhales deeply]
[exhales deeply]
NOW... HE'S HERE.
I CAN FEEL HIM.
HECTOR...
WHO DO YOU WISH
TO SPEAK TO?
[gasps]
[exhales deeply]
THE KILLER'S HERE.
KNOW THIS--
HECTOR BRAVA SAYS...
VENGEANCE WILL COME.
YOUR BLOOD WILL SPILL...
[Patrick exhales deeply]BEFORE THE RISING SUN.
OHH. I SENSE HIM.
[exhales deeply]
I-I CAN ALMOST SEE
AN IMAGE.
I-I-IT'S HAZY.
OH, IT...
OHH,
IT'S AS IF IT COULD JUST--
HECTOR. HECTOR, WAIT.
STOP. DON'T GO.
SHOW US
WHO THE KILLER IS.
THERE IT IS.
A DOOR.
"EMPLOYEES ONLY."
AND AN EMPTY HALLWAY.
[footsteps echoing]
FOOTSTEPS... CLOSE...
CLOSE...
[thud]
AAH! UGH![gasps] OH!
I SEE YOU.
[Richard exhales deeply]
I'M SORRY.
MAN, YOU SCARED ME
TO DEATH WITH THAT.
[chuckles] WHEW.IT'S OKAY.
YOU CAN RELAX, BIGELOW.
IT'S OVER. I KNOW
IT WAS YOU THAT DID IT.WHAT, BECAUSE I GOT FRANTIC
AND FELL OUT OF MY CHAIR?
BECAUSE YOU MANAGED
BRAVA'S CORRESPONDENCE,
YOU WERE THE FIRST ONE
TO READ CARMEN'S LETTERS, YES?
YOU SET BRAVA UP
ON A DATE WITH SALLY
AND HAD HER PRETEND TO BE
CARMEN, AND THEN YOU TOLD BRAVA
THAT HE HAD SEX
WITH HIS OWN DAUGHTER.LORD.
AND THEN THE REAL DEAL
SHOWED UP,
SO YOU FAKED CARMEN'S MESSAGE,
AND WHEN BRAVA WALKED THROUGH
THAT SERVICE DOOR,
YOU KILLED HIM.
[Lisbon] AND YOU KILLED
POOR SALLY ALVAREZ
TO COVER YOUR TRACKS.[Patrick] MM-HMM.
AND NOW YOU'LL PAY
FOR THE CRIME YOU COMMITTED.
YOUR BLOOD WILL SPILL
BEFORE THE SUN RISES.
THAT PART
I'M NOT SO SURE ABOUT.
[Bigelow]
IT CAME IN THE MAIL.
JUST OUT OF THE BLUE.
JUST A...
LETTER DESCRIBING AN AFFAIR
BRAVA HAD 20 YEARS AGO,
NAMING THE WOMAN
AND THE PLACE.
AND THAT CAME FROM CARMEN REYES.
THE REAL CARMEN.
THAT GAVE YOU
ALL THE FACTS YOU NEEDED--
THINGS ABOUT THE AFFAIR
THAT ONLY BRAVA
AND CARMEN'S MOTHER WOULD KNOW.
RIGHT?YEAH.
SO WHY'D YOU DO IT?
WHY PUT A MAN
THROUGH THAT KIND OF SUFFERING?
WAS IT THE MONEY?
OR DID YOU JUST LIKE
HAVING BRAVA IN YOUR POWER?
DO YOU KNOW I'VE BEEN RUNNING
NUMBERS ON TRAFFICKING FOR BRAVA
AND SETTING HIM UP ON HIS DATES
FOR, LIKE, FIVE YEARS?
AND DO YOU THINK THAT HE EVER,
EVER THANKED ME?
SAID, "I'M SORRY"?
SAID, "I'M GONNA MAKE THIS UP
TO YOU ONE DAY, RUSSELL"?
I KNEW SALLY
FROM A WHOREHOUSE
UP IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
I TOLD HER
IF SHE PRETENDED TO BE CARMEN,
WE COULD BLACKMAIL BRAVA
AND SPLIT THE MONEY.
THE LETTER JUST GAVE US
EVERYTHING WE NEEDED
TO MAKE BRAVA THINK THAT SHE
WAS THE REAL DEAL. [chuckles]
AND HE WAS NOT ONE FOR ASKING
A WHOLE LOT OF QUESTIONS, SO...
THEN THE REAL CARMEN
SHOWED UP.
YEAH.
HE CALLED ME
AS SOON AS SHE LEFT HIS ROOM,
FREAKED. SO I PLAYED DUMB.
BUT THEN THE NEXT MORNING,
HE CALLED ME
AND HE SAID,
"WE NEED TO TALK."
IT WAS PRETTY CLEAR
HE FIGURED IT OUT.
AND SO YOU WENT TO THE HOTEL
AND TEXTED BRAVA
FROM THE SERVICE HALLWAY.
[crash]
I JUST--I JUST WANTED
TO KEEP HIM QUIET.
AND SALLY ALVAREZ?
YOU HAD TO KEEP HER QUIET,
TOO, RIGHT?
YOU KNOW,
I WAS A REALLY GOOD RESEARCHER.
I BET.
COME ON.
AGENT VAN PELT,
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME?
OH, YEAH. HI, CARMEN.
I JUST WANTED TO GO OVER
A FEW THINGS IN YOUR STATEMENT.
LET'S GO IN THE KITCHEN.
SO... [sighs]
NICE WORKING WITH YOU.
YEAH.
YEAH, YOU WERE VERY GOOD
BACK THERE.
UH, YOU ALMOST HAD ME
WITH THE WHOLE
"I CAN'T MISUSE MY GIFT FOR FEAR
OF WHAT MIGHT HAPPEN" BIT.
I DID WHAT I SAID I WOULD.
I SPOKE THE WORDS THE SPIRITS
TOLD ME TO SPEAK, NOTHING MORE.
REALLY?
DON'T YOU KNOW ME BY NOW?
DON'T YOU KNOW I WOULDN'T LIE
ABOUT A THING LIKE THAT?
MS. FRYE,
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE COULDN'T HAVE CLOSED THIS ONE
WITHOUT YOU.WELL, THAT'S DEBATABLE.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
ALTHOUGH I HAVE TO SAY
IT LOOKS LIKE THE SPIRITS
GOT IT WRONG.
I GUESS BEING DEAD
DOESN'T MAKE YOU INFALLIBLE.WELL, WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THE KILLER WAS CAUGHT,
AND JUSTICE WAS SERVED.
SURE.
BUT NO BLOOD WAS SPILLED.
LOOK, HE'S RIGHT THERE.
[crunch]HEY! HEY, HEY!
MURDERER! [grunts]
OH!
[gasping]
OH, COME ON.
THAT WAS PURE LUCK.
ADMIT IT.
IF YOU SAY SO.
OH, I KNOWSO.
THE DEAD ARE DEAD.
YOU CAN'T TALK TO THEM.
AND YET I DO.
YEAH...
YOU'RE VERY GOOD.
I GO THIS WAY.
OKAY.IT WAS NICE
SEEING YOU AGAIN.
YOU, TOO.
BYE.
KRISTINA?
YES.
THAT'S WITH A "K," RIGHT?
YOU WANNA GO GET A COFFEE?
I'LL DRINK TEA MYSELF,
BUT YOU CAN DRINK
AS MUCH COFFEE AS YOU WANT.YEAH, I'D LIKE THAT.
I CAN'T RIGHT NOW, THOUGH.
I-I HAVE TO BE SOMEWHERE ELSE.
UH, MAYBE SOME OTHER TIME?
SOME OTHER TIME.
SORRY, NOT "MAYBE."
DEFINITELY.
SOMETIME SOON.
CALL ME.
STAY TUNED FOR SCENES
FROM OUR NEXT EPISODE.